Guide to the Foundations' Fund for Research in Psychiatry Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Foundations' Fund for Research in Psychiatry
1953-1985
RU 484
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
21
The records consist of minutes, annual reports, articles, grant proposals and reports, and financial statements documenting the operations of the Foundations' Fund for Research in Psychiatry.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 37 (YRG 37), Records of associations, institutes, centers, and organizations affiliated with Yale University.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the Foundations' Fund for Research in Psychiatry, 1981-1986.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged as follows: Series I. Minutes of the Board of Directors and Fellowship Committee. Series II. Annual Reports. Series III. Reprints of Publications Reporting Research Supported by Foundations' Fund. Series IV. Reprints of Publications Reporting Research Supported by Ford Foundation Training and Block Grants. Series V. Final Grant Reports; and subsequent accessions.
Biographical / Historical
The Foundations' Fund for Research in Psychiatry (FFRP) was established in 1953 by the Social Research Foundation. Yale Corporation served as trustee and custodian. The purpose of the FFRP was to to support research in psychiatry through a grant program. The FFRP ceased operations in 1981.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of minutes, annual reports, articles, grant proposals and reports, and financial statements documenting the operations of the Foundations' Fund for Research in Psychiatry.
Medicine -- Research grants; Medicine -- Research; Psychiatry -- Research grants; Psychiatry -- Research; Psychology -- Research grants; Psychology -- Research; Foundations' Fund for Research in Psychiatry
- Minutes of the Board of Directors and Fellowship Committee, 1953-1978; Series I
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  Scope and Contents
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Board of Directors Minutes
    - 1953 Mar-1957 Oct (Box 1)
    - 1956 Feb-1957 Oct (Box 1)
    - 1958 Jan-1959 Jan (Box 1)
    - 1959Oct -1962 May (Box 2)
    - 1962 Oct-1964 May (Box 2)
    - 1964 Nov-1966 Nov (Box 2)
    - 1967 Jan-1969 Feb (Box 3)
    - 1969Jun-1970Oct (Box 3)
    - 1971 Feb-1972 Jun (Box 3)
    - 1972 Nov- 1974Apr (Box 4)
    - 1974 Nov - 1977 Mar (Box 5)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 5)
  - Fellowship Committee Minutes
    - 1956 May-1958Apr (Box 6)
    - 1959 Jan - 1961 Apr (Box 6)
- Annual reports, Series II
  Broad overview of the Fund's purpose, policies, and year to year funding activities.
  - 1953-1954 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 1954-1955 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 1955-1956 and "Program of Training Grants" pamphlet (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - 1956-1957 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - 1957-1958 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - 1955-1959 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - 1959-1960 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - 1960-1961 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - 1961-1962 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - 1962-1963 "Tenth Annual Report for the years 1953-1963" (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - 1963-1964 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - 1964-1965 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - 1965-1966 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - 1966-1967 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - 1967-1966 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - 1963-1969 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - 1972-1973 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - 1974-1975 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - 1975-1976 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - 1976-1977 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - 1977-1978 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - 1978-1979 (Box 10, Folder 26)
- Reprints of publications reporting research supported by FFRP, Series III
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2016
  - Reprints from grants
    - 69-444 to 69-471 (Box 24)
- Reprints of publications reporting research supported by Ford Foundation training and block grants, Series IV
  - Reprints from grants
    - T 56-51 to T 59-125 (Box 29)
    - T 59-126 t o T 60-159 (Box 30)
    - T 60-161 to T61-189 (Box 31)
    - T 61-190 t o T 64-206 (Box 32)
  - Reprints from grants B 58-01 t o B 60-42 (Box 33)
- Final Grant Reports, Series V
  - Final reports
    - 69-444 to 69-469 (Box 36, Folder 21)
  - Final reports
    - T 57-74 (Box 38, Folder 33)
    - T 59-122 to T 59-128 (Box 38, Folder 34)
    - T 60-153 t o T 60-156 (Box 38, Folder 35)
  - Fellowship grants, final reports (bound volume) (Box 40)
- Foundations Fund for Research in Psychiatry, 1953-1985; Accession 19ND-A-422; 1; (1 box) (Box 1)
- Records, 1953-1981; Accession 1981-A-062
- Records, 1953-1983; Accession 1982-A-004
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2018
  - "FERP and the Growth of Research in Psychiatry" Maya Pines, 1983 January (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Final Report, 1953-1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes vol. 12, 1977-1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Records, 1955-1985; Accession 1986-A-105
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2020
  - Agreement and Declaration of Trust By-Laws of FFRP, 1964-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1971-1984
    - International Exchange of Journals/ Grant 72-561 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Yale University/ Grant 73-575 Morton F. Relser, M.D. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - California Institute of Technology/ Grant 74-584 Yadin Dudal, Ph.D Canceled (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - University of Queensland Grant 74-586 B. G. Burton-Bradley, M.D. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - University of Rochester/ Grant 74-587 Clara P. Baldwin, Ph.D (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Children's Hospital Medical center/ Grant 74-589 Francois Rieger, Ph.D. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - University of California, San Fransisco Grant 74-591 Charles A. Garfield, Ph.D (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - University of Chicago/ Grant 74-592 Carol T. Hengveld, M.D. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - University of California, Davis/ Grant 74-593 Alan M. Ratner, Ph.D. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - National Institute for Medical Research, London/ Grant 74-594 Efrain C. Azmitia, Jr., Ph.D. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Columbia university/ Grant 74-595 Thomas J. Carew, Ph.D. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - University of Pennsylvania/ Grant 74-596 David D. Burns, M.D. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Pu'ortheastern University/ Grant 74-597 - Helen Mahut, Ph.D. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Center For Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences/ Grant 74 - 59 8 Gardner Lindzey, Ph.D. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Psychoactive Drugs in the Blood / Grant 76-599 Planning Grant (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Executive Discretionary Grant/ Grant 76-601 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Yale University Grant 76-602 Robert J. Lifton, M.D. (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - American Psychiatric Association/ Grant 76-603 Annual Prize Award (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - University of California, Los Angeles/ Grant 77-605 Fritz Redlich, M.D. (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Dartmouth Medical School/ Grant 77-606 Peter J. Hauri, Ph.D. (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - University of Southern California/ Grant 77-607 R. Bruce Sloan, M.D. (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Center for Advanced Study in the. Behayioral Sciences/Grant 77-608 Seymour S. Kety, M.D. (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Administrative Discretionary Grant/ Grant 77-609 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - University of Chicago/ Grant 77-610 John M. Davis, M.D. (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - New York State Psychiatric Institute/ Grant 77-612 James M. Perel, Ph.D; TRANSFERRED to: Western Psychiatric Institute and Clinic, Pittsburgh, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Unlversity of California, Los Angeles / Grant 77-613 Philip R. A. May, Ph.D. (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - University of Utah/ Grant 77-614 Eugene L. Bliss, M.D. (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - University of California, Los Angeles/ Grant 77-616 Fritz Redlich, M.D. (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Administrative Discretionary Grant/ Grant 77-617 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Unniversity of Iowa/ Grant 78-619 Ming.T. Tsuang, N.D. Ph.D (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - University of South Carolina/ Grant 782621 Ronald.We Maris, Ph.D (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - University of Oregon/ Grant 78-622 James B. Shore, M.D. (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Stanford University/ Grant 78-623 Thomas F. Anders, M.D. (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - University of Wisconsin/ Grant 78-624 James R, Greenfey, Ph.D (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - International Conference in Psychopharmacology/ Grant 78-625, 1979 May (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - University of California, Los Angeles/ Grant 78-630 Fritz Redlich, M.D. (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Institute for Advanced Research in Asian Science and Medicine/ Grant 79-631 John J. Kao, M.D. (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - State University of New York, Stonybrook/ Grant,79-632 Richard Green, M.D. (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Boston University/ Grant 79-633 David I. Mostofsky, Ph.D (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - University of California, San Diego / Grant-79-634 Igor Grant, M.D. (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - University of California, Los Angeles/ Grant 79-635 Seymour Feshbach, Ph.D (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - University of Washington/ Grant 79-636 Ann P. Streissguth, Ph.D. (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Boston University-Yale university/ Grant 79-638 A. Klevorich, Ph-D and T. McGuire, Ph.D (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - University of Pennsylvania/ Grant 79-639 Paul Taubman, Ph.D and Ann Bartel, Ph.D (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Institute of Society, Ethics, and the Life Sciences/ Grant 79-640 Willard Gaylin, M.D. (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - University of Wisconsin/ Grant 80-648 Elaine Hatfield, Ph.D CANCELLED (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - University of Wisconsin/ Grant 79-642 Burton 0. Weisbrod, Ph.D (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - University of California, Los Angeles Grant 79-643 W.J. Winslade, Ph.D and L. H. Roth, M.D. (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Administrative Discretionary Fund/ Grant 79-646 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - University of California, Los Angeles Grant 79-645 Fritz Redlich, M.D. (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - University of Rochester/ Grant 80-648 Rue Cromwell, Ph.D (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - State University of New York, Buffalo/ Grant 80-649 Murray Levine, Ph.D (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Yale Universlty Grant 80-650 Kenneth K. Kidd, Ph.D. (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - University of California, Los Angeles/ Grant 80-651 Joe Yamamoto, M.D. (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Independent--Center for Advanced Study In the Behavioral sciences/ Program of Conferences and Fellowships (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Endowment--Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences/ Consortium, Wood Kalb Foundation (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Senior Research Professorships, 1957-1961 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Research Position Grant RP60-173 University of Utah/ Eugene L. Bliss, M.D, 1960-1975 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Research Position RP60-174 Columbia University / Ernest M. Gruenberg, M.D. TERMINATED, 1975 June (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Research Position Grant W 60-175 Yale University / Robert J. Lifton, M.D., 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Research Position Grant. RP 60-176 University of Chicago / Lawrence Z. Freedman, M.D., 1960-1985 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Program Grant PG63-192 University College of the West Indes, Jamaica, 1963-1980 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Child Development Grant T64-205 University of Kentucky, 1963-1974 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Child Development Grant T64-206 Howard University, 1963-1967 (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Child Development Grant T64-207 University of Oklahoma, 1964-1973 (Box 2, Folder 93)